Marshall Brown

marshallendel@gmail.com
317.922.7046
Indianapolis, IN
marshlendel.github.io/portfolio/
linkedin.com/marshall-brown

Objective:

I am a web developer with a passion for people, solving problems and a desire to learn. I have experience creating full-stack applications using JavaScript and am quick at learning new technologies. I am in search for a junior web development position where I can continue to improve my skills and grow with a community.

Education:

- Eleven Fifty Academy, Web Development Immersive Learning Program, Indianapolis, IN, June September 2021
 - 12-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training
- Indiana Wesleyan University, Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Systems, Marion, IN, May 2021

Competencies & Functional Skills:

Problem solving, adaptability, leadership, creativity, verbal communication, detail oriented, critical observation and thinking, organization, Agile methodology, collaboration, teamwork, addressing and resolving business challenges, confident

Technical Skills:

Languages: JavaScript, Node.JS, React, Heroku & Firebase deployment, TypeScript deployment

CI/CD: Agile, Scrum, Git, terminal PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, APIs, stateless components, session validation, responsive web design

Technical Projects:

- ElevenFifty Academy Static website: https://marshlendel.githumjb.io/static-layout/
 - o Utilized vanilla HTML 5, CSS 3, and JavaScipt to recreate a static version of the EFA website
- GIPH Generator: https://api2-d43e0.web.app/
 - Utilized Bootstrap, JavaScript and the GIPHY API to display a list of gipgs based on a search query
- Fullstack Movie Watch List App: https://flick-list-client-mb.herokuapp.com/
 - Utilized PostgreSQL Database, Express.js, React, and Node.js to create a full-stack CRUD app in which you can create an account, log-in, search for movies and then add them to a watch list.
- Fullstack Chat App: https://hoosier-holler.herokuapp.com/

Professional Experience:

- Marketing Intern, Proof Digital, Indianapolis, IN, Jan 2021 May 2021
 - Lead Generation: Curated a list of qualified leads into a Google spreadsheet
 - Utilizied A to Z Databases to conduct prospect research based on specific critierea

Followed safety protocols to load pressed truck parts onto racks to be shipped

- SEO: Learned how to use Semrush to conduct effective keyword research
- Production Associate, General Motors, Marion, IN December 2020 May 2021
 - Performed quality checks on parts to check for dents, tears and other defects
- o Crew Leader, Practical Property Group LLC, Westfield, IN May 2020 August 2020
 - Operated water truck to irrigate sod and maintain plants around neighborhood
 - Led crew members to mulch, water and cleanup flower beds
- Sales Representative, Vector Marketing, Indianapolis, IN December 2019 January 2020
 - Booked calls over the phone with prospects and scheduled in-person appointments
 - Sold over \$2500 worth of Cutco over 1 week, earning the Top 5 Sales Rep of The Week award
- Technician Intern, Netlink Inc (COVI), Indianapolis, IN, June 2018 August 2018
 - Improved, optimized and updated computer systems, installed new components, troubleshot computer errors and checked for faulty hardware.
- Math Tutor, The Excel Center, Indianapolis, IN May 2017 August 2017
 - Worked personally with struggling students and created unique plans to boost their comprehension